One singular sensation!
A Chorus Line is a drama, music film directed by Richard Attenborough.
A group of dancers congregate on the stage of a Broadway theatre to
audition for a new musical production directed by Zach.
After the initial eliminations, seventeen hopefuls remain, among them Cassie,
who once had a tempestuous romantic relationship with Zach.
She is desperate enough for work to humble herself and audition for him; whether he's willing to let
professionalism overcome his personal feelings about their past remains to be seen.
Zach, played by Michael Douglas.
Cassie, played by Alyson Reed.
Larry, played by Terrence Mann.
Richie, played by Gregg Burge.
Sheila, played by Vicki Frederick.
Bebe, played by Michelle Johnston.
A Chorus Line is a 1985 American musical drama film directed by Richard
Attenborough, and starring Michael Douglas and Terrence Mann.
The screenplay by Arnold Schulman is based on the book of
the 1975 stage musical by James Kirkwood Jr.
and Nicholas Dante.
The songs were composed by Marvin Hamlisch and Edward Kleban.
The plot centers on a group of dancers auditioning
for a part in a new Broadway musical.
Released theatrically by Columbia Pictures on December 9, 1985, the film
received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $14.2 million.
The film explores themes of musical, stage show,
backstage, urban setting, top hat.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.